Hello English learners and
welcome to English pod.
My name's Erica and I'm here with Marco.
Marco hurry up.
I'm coming.
Hurry up Marco.
We've got a lesson.
Okay.
I'm here.
What did I miss?
The lesson.
All right.
Sorry about that.
We have a great lesson for you today.
We have an elementary lesson.
That's right, an elementary
lesson about being
in a rush and about giving
directions when you're in a car.
Exactly.
We're going to listen
to two friends who are
getting in a car and
they're getting ready
to go somewhere and
they're in a big hurry.
So let's hurry up and
listen to the dialogue.
Hurry up.
Get in.
Okay.
Make a left here.
No wait.
I meant make a right.
Come on.
Speed up.
Dees.
What's the rush?
Don't worry about it.
Just drive.
No.
The light is about to change.
Step on it.
Are you nuts?
I'm not going to run a red light.
Whatever.
Just turn right here.
The freeway will be packed at this hour.
Let's take a side street.
Go on.
Get out of our way.
Move.
What's your problem?
Jeez.
Having a fit is not going to help.
Here.
I know a shortcut.
Just go down here and we'll
cut through Ashburn Heights.
Let's go.
Watch out for that lady.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Yes.
We made it.
558 just before the library closes.
You're such a geek.
So they were in a hurry and it
was all just to get to the library.
Well, maybe he was late
returning a book or something.
That's a bit dramatic
just for returning a book.
Yeah.
All right.
Why don't we look at our
language takeaway for today?
Language takeaway.
Okay, on today's
language takeaway, we have
five words for you
today, five really important
and useful words that
we found in our dialogue.
So let's take a look at the first one.
Step on it.
So what does it mean
when I tell you to step on it?
Drive faster.
Drive faster, right?
Step on it.
Exactly.
You might also say speed up.
Speed up.
Yes.
Exactly it.
Our second word speed up.
Also means go faster.
Go faster.
And what about the opposite?
You might say slow down.
Slow down.
Yeah.
Okay.
So speed up and slow down.
So our third word for
today is having a fit.
Having a fit.
Well, this is a funny phrase.
And I think listening
to a few examples of this
phrase might help us understand
its meaning a little bit better.
Example one.
Jeez.
You don't need to have a fit.
Nothing is going to happen
if we're five minutes late.
All two.
My boss is going to have a
fit if I don't finish this on time.
Example three.
I almost had a fit when my boss
told me I had to work this weekend.
Okay.
Great examples.
Like a, why don't you tell me what
does it mean when you have a fit?
It means you get really angry and
you can't control your emotions.
So maybe you start screaming and
maybe some steam comes out of your ears.
Okay.
That's having a fit.
Exactly.
Excellent.
Okay.
Let's take a look at our next word now.
Cut through.
So when you cut through something, it
means you just go through, go through.
Yeah.
Quite simple.
It gives you the idea that you
go through something quickly.
Quickly.
So I can say let's cut through the park.
Yep.
Or let's cut through the backyard.
Okay.
Go through.
And this takes us to
our last word for today.
Short cut.
Cut.
This is a really common word
and not many people know about it.
Yeah.
You're right.
It's two simple words that when you
fit them together, the meaning changes.
It's a great example of this
real English we talk about.
And it means to take a
shorter way somewhere.
Exactly.
So if I take a short
cut, I go the short way.
Okay.
So going back just a
little bit to cut through.
If I cut through the park,
that's basically a short cut.
Exactly.
All right.
Now it's clear.
Okay.
Now it's time to
listen to our dialogue
again, but this time
it's going to be slower.
So then we can understand all
these words that we just talked about.
Hurry up.
Get in.
I'm in.
Let's go.
Okay.
Make a left here.
No, wait.
I meant make a right.
Come on.
Speed up.
Jeez.
What's the rush?
Don't worry about it.
Just drive.
Oh, no.
The light is about to change.
Step on it.
Are you nuts?
I'm not going to run a red light.
Whatever.
Just turn right here.
The freeway will be packed at this hour.
Let's take a side street.
Gone.
Get out of our way.
Move.
What's your problem?
Jeez.
Having a fit is not going to help.
Here.
I know a shortcut.
Just go down here and we'll
cut through Ashburn Heights.
Let's go.
Watch out for that lady.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Yes.
We made it 558 just
before the library closes.
You're such a geek.
Okay.
Well, I think that with a
lot more clear this time.
You know there was
some great language in
that dialogue and I would like to
look at how we can put it together.
Putting it together.
Okay.
So today I'm putting it together.
We have three phrases for you.
And we're going to show you how you can
use these phrases like a native speaker.
Okay.
So all of these
phrases we heard in the
dialogue, why don't we
start with the first one?
Make a make a so in the
dialogue, they say make a left here.
Yeah.
And we can extend this
phrase to say make a right.
That would be the equivalent of
saying turn left or turn right turn right.
And there's one more, make a you turn.
Exactly.
That means turn the car 180
degrees all the way around.
Make a you turn.
So make a left, make a
right, make a you turn.
If you're ever in a taxi
and you're telling the
taxi driver where to go,
this is the perfect way.
Make a left here, make a right there.
Okay.
So let's move to our second
phrase and it is are you nuts?
Are you nuts?
So this is a great way
of saying are you crazy?
Are you insane?
Are you mad?
So when would we use a phrase like this?
If somebody has a
bad idea that you don't
agree with, you would say
are you crazy or are you nuts?
So Marco, let's stop
this podcast right now.
Are you nuts?
Okay.
I think that's a good example
of how we can use this phrase.
Yes.
So are you nuts?
Are you insane?
Are you mad?
So let's listen to some
examples of are you nuts?
Example one.
You want to get married now?
Are you nuts?
You only met her three weeks ago.
Example two.
Are you nuts?
I'm not going to cheat on the exam.
What if I get caught?
So I think that's clear.
And now we can move to our third
phrase, which is let's take a side street.
Let's take a side street.
Again, so if you're
in a taxi, this is a great
way to suggest a route
or suggest a direction.
So we can take this phrase and
extend it out with a few more words.
We might say let's take Wilson Avenue.
Right, or let's take the highway.
So let's take a side street.
Let's take Wilson Avenue.
Let's take the freeway.
OK, so now let's take a listen to this
dialogue a third time at its normal speed.
And now you can understand
everything that's in this dialogue.
Hurry up.
Get in.
OK, make a left here.
No wait.
I meant make a right.
Come on, speed up.
Tease.
What's the rush?
Don't worry about it.
Just drive.
No.
The light is about to change.
Step on it.
Are you nuts?
I'm not going to run a red light.
Whatever, just turn right here.
The freeway will be packed at this hour.
Let's take a side street.
Go on.
Get out of our way.
Move, move.
What's your problem?
Geez, having a fit is not going to help.
Here, I know a shortcut.
Just go down here and we'll
cut through Ashburn Heights.
Let's go.
Watch out for that lady.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Yes, we made it.
558, just before the library closes.
You're such a geek.
Well, this dialogue is
all about driving, right?
Yes.
And in North America,
we're both of us are from.
Driving is everything.
Everybody has a car.
When did you get a car?
I-- well, my car I got when I was maybe 19.
Really?
But I learned how to drive and I
was driving already by the age of 16.
Yeah, that's the thing.
In many countries, you have to
wait till I think you're 18 to drive.
But in North America,
everyone has a driver's
license by the time
they're 16 years old.
Yeah, yeah.
I guess everything is so
far away that you need a car.
It's a lot less likely to have subways
or trains to travel by in North America.
All right, so now you
have all the tools necessary
to give directions the next
time you're in a car or in a taxi.
Well, everyone, I really
hope you enjoyed this lesson.
Now, I want to remind you all to come to
our English pod website at EnglishPod.com.
And here you'll find a lot of tools to
help you understand our podcast better.
So with that, until next
time, this is goodbye.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]